(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-13T09:18:24.411390",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆声援送ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for sending your cheers!
最初はこの勢い目から始めます キャッチーモーメント
We'll start with this momentum: Catch the Moment!
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sighs I breathed out,
後悔は苦い味残して
leaving behind the bitter taste of regret.
いつも なんで? 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it that, always, I can't say the crucial things,
次の朝日が顔出してる
while the next morning's sun shows its face?
嫌になった運命を ナイフで切り刻んで
Carving up the fate I grew to hate with a knife,
もう一度やり直したら キミに出会えないかも
if I started over once more, maybe I wouldn't meet you.
僕の声が響いた 瞬間に始まる
The moment my voice resounded, it all begins,
命のリミット 心臓が
with life's limit counting down
カウントしてる 叶えても叶えても 終わらない願い
in my heart. Wishes that never end, no matter how many come true.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は いつか止まった僕を置いていく
The world's second hand, running in sweat, leaves behind a stopped me.
あと何回キミと笑えるの? 試してんだろ ボクを Catch the Moment
How many more times can I smile with you? It's testing me, Catch the Moment.
一個幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a piece of happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I grow afraid of the changing future,
愛情の種を 大切に育てよう
but let's nurture the seeds of love with care.
分厚い雲も やがて突き破るかな
Surely, they'll eventually pierce through the thick clouds.
キミの声が響いた ボクの全身を通って
Your voice resounded, passing through my entire body,
心臓のドアをノックしてる
knocking on the door of my heart.
「怯え」でも開けちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
Even "cowardice" can open it up, because I want to believe.
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に いつか深く確かな根を生やす 嵐の夜が来たとしても 揺らいだりはしない何度でも
Where I thought there was nothing at the soles of my feet, deep, certain roots grow. Even if a stormy night comes, I will never waver, no matter how many times.
キミの声が響いた 時に始まる
When your voice resounds, it all begins,
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
with life's limit counting down in my heart.
叶えても 叶えても 終わらない願い
Wishes that never end, no matter how many come true.
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sighs I spit out,
後悔は苦い味残して
Regrets only left a bitter taste.
いつも なんて? 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why? Always like this, unable to say what matters.
次の朝日が顔を出してる
As the next morning sun shows its face.
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
Slicing up the destiny I grew to hate with a knife,
もう一度やり直したら キミに出会えないかも
If I restarted, maybe I wouldn't meet you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる 命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The moment my voice echoes, life's limit begins, my heart is counting down.
叶えても叶えても 終わらない願い
Wishes that never end, no matter how many come true.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は いつか止まった僕を置いていく
Running in sweat, the world's second hand leaves me behind where I stopped.
あと何回キミと笑えるの? 試してるんだ僕を Catch the Moment
How many more times can I smile with you? It's testing me, Catch the Moment.
今日は楽しんでいってね！
Enjoy today to the fullest!
はいはいはいはいはいはいどうもみなさん！
Hey hey hey hey hey hey, hello everyone!
ゴーストルール 決めちゃいます
We're deciding on Ghost Rule!
最初のリクエスト！ よろしくお願いします！
Let's go!
どうだっていいことを
Whatever doesn't matter,
嘘って吐いて戻れない
I lied and spat out, now I can't go back.
時効なんてやってこない
The statute of limitations never comes.
奪ったように奪われて
Having things taken just as I took them,
今日だってかなわない
Today won't work out either.
想ったようにだませない
I can't deceive the way I want to.
腐っている僕には 腐ったものがわからない
Rotten as I am, I can't tell what is rotten.
おいで ここまで ステイ
Come here, stay right here.
隠してしまったんだ
I ended up hiding it away.
Hey Mayday! 僕とわかっても
Hey Mayday! Even if you know it's me,
もう抱きしめなくていいんだよ
You don't need to hold me close anymore.
Hey Mayday! 僕がわかったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな
Hey Mayday! If you figure out it's me, will you smile at me once more?
まぼろしだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's just an illusion,
うそつきだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a pack of lies,
ねぇ
Hey...
うそつきだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a pack of lies,
どうだっていいことを
Whatever doesn't matter,
嘘だって言えそうにない
I can't seem to say it's a lie.
後悔の静寂は
The silence of regret
保ったほうがセイタなの
is better kept intact.
臆病だって構わない
I don't care if I'm a coward,
祈っておいてそれは無い
Praying and then doing that is wrong.
砕いていた情熱が ボケッと突っ立ってるだけさ
The passion I shattered is just standing there blankly.
Hey Mayday! どこまでグレい
Hey Mayday! How far will you stray?
被害者ぶったって
Even if you play the victim,
Hey Mayday! 僕を叱ってよ
Hey Mayday! Scold me,
正直者が夢みたいなら 最後まで甘えにしちゃうのは
If honesty is like a dream, pampering myself until the very end...
まぼろしだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's just an illusion,
うそつきだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a pack of lies,
足らないものを望んだら
If you wish for what you lack,
僕じゃない僕に出会ったよ
You'll meet a "me" that isn't me.
それでも前に進んだの
Even so, you moved forward.
くらくらしちゃう夜も
Even on nights when you feel dizzy,
足らない僕を愛してよ
Love this inadequate me.
エゴマナカ僕を育てたの
My ego nurtured me.
キミには僕が見えるから
Because you can see me,
孤独なピエロが
A lonely clown...
Hey Mayday! 僕とわかっても もう抱きしめなくていいんだよ
Hey Mayday! Even if you know it's me, you don't need to hold me close anymore.
Hey Mayday! 僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢みたいなら
Hey Mayday! Scold me, if being honest is like a dream.
Hey Mayday! 僕を忘れてよ 最後まで甘えにしちゃうのは
Hey Mayday! Forget me, giving in to pampering until the very end...
Hey Mayday! 僕を殺してよ もう時期終わるこの世界から
Hey Mayday! Kill me, from this world that's ending soon.
Hey Mayday! 僕と踊ってよ 最初からいないとわかってた
Hey Mayday! Dance with me, knowing I wasn't there from the start.
まぼろしだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's just an illusion,
うそつきだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a pack of lies,
亡霊だって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a ghost,
空白だって知るんだよ
Knowing it's a void,
どうだっていいことを 嘘って吐いて戻れない
Whatever doesn't matter, I lied and spat out, now I can't go back.
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
The statute of limitations never comes, having things taken just as I took them.
今夜優しくノックして乗り込め 心心の奪還戦
Knock gently tonight and break in, a recapture battle of hearts.
妄想ばかりがフラッシュして 加速するパルス 答えはどこだろう
Only delusions flash, a pulse accelerating, where is the answer?
さあさあ弱音はミュートして くだらないことで躊躇して
Now now, mute your complaints, hesitating over trivial things.
冗談ばかりね？ ああはあは
Just joking around, huh? Ah-ha, ah-ha.
コンコン 優しくノックして
Knock, knock, a polite little knock,
乗り込め ココロの強奪戦
stealing your heart in a raid.
妄想ばかりが 加速するバルス
Delusions are accelerating, what a pulse!
答えはどこだろう
Where is the answer supposed to be?
さあさ弱音はミュートして
Mute your excuses, come on!
冗談ばかりね?あははっ
Just a joke? Haha!
壊せない壁がキスを迫るでしょう
An unbreakable wall is forcing a kiss.
鳴呼、厭「そんなわけないや」
"There's no way," you cry out.
鳴呼、厭「わかってくれるでしょ」
"You'll understand," you plead.
その頭を打ち抜いて
Shoot straight through that head of yours!
終わんない愛を抱いていたくないの
I don't want an endless love.
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me feel a little more insecure.
いないいないばぁで演じて欲しいの
Play it out in a flawless place.
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
Respond to me a little better!
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
トントン これで御手相って
Knock, knock, we're even now.
埋まらない時に語っちゃって
Spoken too soon when it can't be filled.
完全主義はスモーキーに
Perfectionism goes up in smoke.
孤立する声に見劣りとモノトーン
Blinded by lonely voices, with a monotone.
Knock knock! レインボー どっちも選んで
Knock, knock! Rainbow, pick either one.
レインボー どっちも壊して
Rainbow, destroy either one.
ココロの根をきき抜いて
Ripping out the roots of my heart.
不機嫌な愛を愛したくないの
I don't want to love a grumpy love.
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it hurt a little more.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even smile.
もっとちゃんと遠くしてよ
Keep it far away a little more.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
不幸な愛を愛したくないの
I don't want to love an unhappy love.
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it hurt a little more.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even smile.
もっとちゃんと遠くしてよ
Keep it far away a little more.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
不機嫌な愛を愛したくないの
I don't want to love a grumpy love.
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it hurt a little more.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even smile.
もっとちゃんと遠くしてよ
Keep it far away a little more.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
不幸な愛を愛したくないの
I don't want to love an unhappy love.
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it hurt a little more.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even smile.
もっとちゃんと遠くしてよ
Keep it far away a little more.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Inside a love that shattered "NO."
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
"It's incomplete," I say over and over.
さあ 睡眠打破
Now, smash the sleeplessness,
昼夜逆転
day and night in reverse.
盛り上がっていこうぜ！
Let's get fired up!
さあ 眠眠打破
Hey, sleeper boy,
昼夜逆転
days and nights inverted,
VOX AC30W
with a Vox AC30.
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが
A sub-culture boy on a Telecaster gig
バンド仲間にやっほー
joining bandmates for a jam.
アルバイトはネクラモード
Part-time work is so emo,
対バンドにはATフィールド
while rivals crush your ego.
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy?
Running away with an "antisocial" plea, boy?
ゆーて お坊ちゃんお嬢ちゃん
Come on, little master and missy,
お金も才能もなまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
money and talent are just a bother.
boys be ambitious... like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
勘違いすんな 教祖はオマエだ
You've got it wrong, your guru is you!
ロキロキのロックロックンロール
Rock-rock-rockin', rock-rock-rock-roll!
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターはdon't stop! don't stop!
Let your electric guitar ring out, don't stop!
さあ君の全てを曝け出してみせろよ
Now show me everything you've got!
ロキロキのロックロックンロール
Rock-rock-rockin', rock-rock-rock-roll!
さあ 日進月歩
Now, day by day, progressing fast,
いい曲書いてる? 動員増えてる?
writing good songs, growing views?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね。」
"I'm known, but not that popular, so it's tough."
はっきり言うなよ匿名アイコン
Speak clearly, anonymous icon!
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Show your real face, real-life icon!
いい歳こいて自意識まだ boy?
Acting mature with an ego, boy?
ぶっちゃけどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
Clever and cunning, but in 10 years,
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
your true colors will show.
boys be ambitious... like this old man
生き残るためだ キメろ take a "selfy"
Your Instagram is on the line, take a "selfy"!
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ お互いにな!
We'll survive together!
ロキロキのロックロックンロール
Rock-rock-rockin', rock-rock-rock-roll!
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいいdon't stop! don't stop!
Even a shallow love song is fine, don't stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Now, strike down the one right in front of you!
ロキロキのロックロックンロール
Rock-rock-rockin', rock-rock-rock-roll!
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
Not satisfied just muddying the waters,
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコードは
brought into the studio on a slow-to-code.
安心 不安気 プレッシャーでいっぱい
Safety, anxiety, full of pressure.
「実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません」
"Actually I've been sick since yesterday."
は?は?は?は?
Huh? What? No way! Shut up!
はぁ… 寝言は寝て言え ベイビー
Keep dreaming, baby!
さあ眠眠破打 昼夜逆転
Wake up, break the sleep, day and night reversed
VOX AC30W
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが
A subcultural boy with a Telecaster on his back
バンド仲間にやっほー
Says hello to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード
His part-time job is in gloomy mode
対バンドにはATフィールド
An AT field against rival bands
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
Are you running away with an "introvert" declaration, boy?
ゆーて お坊っちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
I mean, rich kids, poor kids, money and talent
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
Having just enough is more trouble than it's worth
Boys be ambitious...
...like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者 信者
Follower, follower
勘違いすんなよ 教祖はオマエだ
Make no mistake, you are the guru
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
かき鳴らす エレクトリックギターは
Strumming away, the electric guitar
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Now reveal everything you've got
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
さあ 日進月歩 いい曲書いてる？ 動員ふえてる？
Now, advancing day by day, writing good tunes? Growing your crowd?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね。」
"You have some fame, but not much popularity, so it must be tough."
言うなよ 匿名アイコン
Don't say that, anonymous icon
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Real-life icon who never shows their face clearly
いい歳こいて自意識まだ boy
Still acting like a self-conscious boy at your age
ぶっちゃけどんだけ賢いあざとくやったって
No matter how shrewd and clever you try to be
10年後にメイクは落ちてんどうよ
In 10 years your makeup will wear off, you know
Boys be ambitious... like this old man
生きてくためだ キメろ take a "selfy"
To survive, strike a pose, take a "selfy"
"selfy" "selfy"
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ お互いにさ！
Don't you dare die on me, we're in this together!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい
Even a shallow love song is fine
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Now try to shoot down the girl right before your eyes
照らすは闇 僕らは歩き慣れてきた日々も涙
The light illuminates the darkness, even the tears in our familiar days
夢は安泰な暮らしだが 刺激不足故にタラタラ
Dreams are a peaceful life, but dragging along from lack of excitement
照らすは煙 僕らの歩き慣れていた道はどこだ
Smoke illuminates, where is the path we used to walk?
時はたまに痙攣が 温もりに包まれ只
Time occasionally spasms, simply wrapped in warmth
炎が立つ 導の方へ
The flames rise, toward the guide
思い出すは優しいメロディー
Remembering a gentle melody
永遠はないんだと ないんだと云ふ
Saying that eternity doesn't exist, doesn't exist
それもまたイイねと笑ってみる
Trying to smile, saying that's fine too
輝けばいつかは光も絶える
If it shines, eventually the light will fade
僕らは命の火が消えるその日まで歩いていく
We keep walking until the day the fire of our life goes out
インフェルノ eh... 燃えないんだって 爛々ってどういう？
Inferno, eh... won't burn, they say, what does it mean to burn brightly?
それもまたイイねと 笑ってみる
Trying to smile, saying that's fine too
幾千歳はいつかは 光も絶え
A thousand years will eventually see the light fade
僕らは命の火が 消えるその日まで歩いてく
We keep walking until the day the fire of our life goes out
ところで何故僕らは 思考を急に辞めているんだ
By the way, why did we suddenly stop thinking?
夢は安泰な暮らしだが 知識不足故にハラハラ
Dreams are a peaceful life, but feeling anxious from lack of knowledge
食えばyummy ヨソガに纏り付いたまま朽ちていくんだ
Eat up yummy, decaying while clinging to the sanctuary
ここは業火の中だが 傷跡はヒリつき只
This place is in hellfire, but scars still sting
水面が立つ 光の方へ
Water surface rises, toward the light
手を取るは新しいメモリー
Taking hands is a new memory
夜空が分かたれ 導の方へ
The night sky divides, toward the guide
遮るのは険しいセオリー
Blocking the way is a steep theory
永遠はないんだと ないんだと云ふ
Saying that eternity doesn't exist, doesn't exist
やっぱり苦しいねと 泣いてみる
Trying to cry, saying it really is painful
風船もいつかは 萎むか割れる
Even a balloon will eventually deflate or burst
僕らは命の泉を守り続けて繋いでいく
We keep protecting the source of life and connecting it
インフェルノ eh... 燃えないんだって 爛々ってどういう？
Inferno, eh... won't burn, they say, what does it mean to burn brightly?
いっそ苦しいんだって 泣いてみたいよ
I'd rather cry, saying it's so painful
ぶっちゃけもういいんかつまらなくたって
Honestly, is it fine even if it's boring?
僕らは命の泉を守り続けて繋いでいく
We keep protecting the source of life and connecting it
学びきれずに卒業 伝えきれずに失恋
Graduating without learning everything, failing to confess a broken heart
遊びきれずに決別 面倒くさいが地獄じゃあるまいし
Saying goodbye without playing enough, it's not like hell is that troublesome
音が出る玩具も 痛みを飛ばす魔法も 全部僕にとっての宝物
The toy that makes sound, the magic that blows away pain, all of them are my treasures
永遠はないんだと ないんだと云ふ
Saying that eternity doesn't exist, doesn't exist
僕らは命の火が消えるその日まで歩いていく
We keep walking until the day the fire of our life goes out
インフェルノ eh... 燃えないんだって 爛々ってどういう？
Inferno, eh... won't burn, they say, what does it mean to burn brightly?
Woah...
命の火が
The fire of life
消えるその日まで歩いてく
Walking until the day it goes out
半端ならK.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
So be it, if you're light-hearted
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show!
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね ほら say no
Even if you cry or laugh, just love me, c'mon say no
低音響かせろ
Bring the bass
なんだかなってつまらないこともあるでしょう
Dunno what to say... things tend to get boring
ロンリー論理のノート ハンディ本気脱走
Lonely logic note, handy serious escape
やんなっちゃって泥にbad ご法度だろうが
Can't take this anymore, bad taboo, but drown and drop in mud
溺れて落ちてね
Drown and fall in
そろそろいっか もっと頑張って
It's 'bout time, let's work harder
アガるまでもっと頑張って
Work harder until I get excited
繋がるひとりよりふたり 増えたら安心
Connect, two is better than one, more people, more relieved
心配ないや
No worries
Alright 任せて don't mind
Alright, leave it to me, don't mind
波あり難題 みんなで乗っかっちゃえば
If we all ride the waves of problems,
案外さくっと行っちゃいそう
Perhaps it's easy to solve
半端ならK.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
So be it, if you're light-hearted
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show!
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね ほら say no
Even if you cry or laugh, just love me, c'mon say no
低音響かせろ
Bring the bass
どんな劣等感だて 即興の血小板で
No matter how inferior, with blood platelets of improvisation
抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞い込むんでしょう
Suppress it, charge in, and put it away
Up and downなテンション ねえまいっちゃってんの相当
Up and down tension, hey, you're really messed up
ドバッと噴き出すのは 本音の独り言
It bursts out like a stream of honest mutterings
「別に興味ない」
“I don't care.”
「特に関係ない」
“It doesn't matter.”
塞ぎ込んで 舌尖絶頂へ 合図を奏でて
Closed off, tongue at its peak, play the signal
PrrPrrPrr ほら集まって夜行だ 鳴いていこう
Prr Prr Prr, come on, gather for the night ride, let's sing
どんな劣等感だって そう今日の決勝戦だって
No matter how inferior, with today's decisive battle
最高難度 更新しちゃおうでしょ
Let's update the highest difficulty
Open downのテンション あら見えてんののそうとう
Open down tension, seeing right through
ドバッと噴き出すのは 本音のひとりごと
It bursts out like a stream of honest mutterings
別に興味ない ない 特に関係ない ない
I don't care, it doesn't matter
ぶっかけこんで 絶頂へ
Splash it in, to the climax
PrrPrrPrr 愛風を奏でて
Prr Prr Prr, play the love wind
ほら 集まって 夜行だ
Come on, gather for the night ride
鳴いていこう
Let's sing
半端ならK.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね
Even if you cry or laugh, just love me
ほら say no
C'mon say no
低音響かせろ
Bring the bass
本当は寂しいんだよ
Actually, I'm lonely
今夜も眠れないの
Can't sleep tonight either
声を聞かせて party night
Let me hear your voice, party night
またねのお越しを きっと
Surely looking forward to seeing you again
次回までお元気に
Stay well until next time
ここらでバイバイ let go
Bye for now, let go
踊りでした！ありがとうございました！
That was Odo! Thank you very much!
(CHU-LU CHU-LU CHU-LU PA-YA-PA)
DISCOTHEQUE DISCOTHEQUE
DEEP EMOTION DEEP EMOTION
皆さん 森カリオペです ポルカ先輩 Happy Birthday!
Everyone, it's Mori Calliope! Polka-senpai, Happy Birthday!
Let's go!
SWEETIE DARLIN' 踊りましょう
SWEETIE DARLIN' let's dance
はじける BEAUTY LADY
the bursting beauty lady
生まれ変わって甘い夢 そっと彩りたいの
I want to be reborn and softly color the sweet dream
グラマラスなくちびる ピンク色の艶めくネイル
The glamorous lips and the nails shining in pink
ガラスの向こう側に映る素顔 シュールなDays
The true face reflected on the other side of the mirror, the surreal days
癒えぬままの 孤独を逆撫でする
Stroking against the raw loneliness,
哀しみは怒りへと 行き場求め
sorrow seeks a place to go as anger.
かつて、祈りであった賛歌の歌は
Once a hymn of prayer,
調和失い 心侵すの
it loses harmony and invades the heart.
半端な 強さじゃもはや
Half-hearted strength can no longer
愚かな傲慢ささえ護れない
even protect foolish arrogance.
軽薄な 月が嘲笑う 不穏に揺らぐ正義
Frivolous moon sneers at the unsettlingly swaying justice.
空虚に喘ぎながら
Panting in emptiness,
それでも 希望を狂い求める
still madly seeking hope.
正気を亡くした 聖母は未だ 泣いている
The mad mother is still crying,
微笑み ながら 血の涙零すのか
shedding tears of blood with a smile?
その痛みの所以をここに問う
I ask here for the reason behind that pain.
Never lose your faith
誰が為の マイラ ホラ
for whose sake—Mira, look!
世界は 変わる
The world will change.
チュルチュルチュル パラパッパ
Chur-chur-chur, para-pappa,
ドラマティックな情熱 浅いデジャヴュ
dramatic passion, a shallow deja vu,
滅び続けたがった 空っぽなスウィートストーリー
an empty sweet story longing for destruction.
心の 深く 刻み込む
Carving deeply into the heart,
小さな闇が 遅れても
even if a small darkness comes late,
恋の字も まだ捉えれたなら
if it still manages to grasp even the word "love,"
きっと 果てない空 星屑のシャワーを
surely a shower of stardust from the endless sky
浴び注ぐ
will pour down upon us.
だからハッピー ステーション 目指してゆこう
So let's aim for the happy station!
フィフティ フィフティ あなたと
Fifty-fifty, with you,
百パーセント以上の
more than one hundred percent!
勇気が ここにあると 私もわかる
I know the courage is right here within me.
チュルチュルチュル パラパッパ
Chur-chur-chur, para-pappa,
色褪せぬと コンサバティブな自分
A conservative self that won't fade,
君の愛のままの
staying as your love...
好きでいようずっと
I'll keep loving you forever.
願いは 救われるから
Because wishes will be saved...
人の波を すり抜けて
Slipping through the waves of people,
誰もがもっと 一緒に踊りましょう secret night
Everyone, let's dance together more on this secret night!
素敵なラブソングのデコレーション
A decoration of a wonderful love song,
二人のハートで奏で合わせて
played in harmony with both our hearts.
騒ぎ鳴らせば 弾けるセクシービート
If you make a noise, a sexy beat bursts out!
生まれ変わって 甘い夢
Reborn into a sweet dream,
外の色どりのマイラ ホラ
the outer colorful Mira, look!
世界は 変わる
The world changes.
チュルチュルチュル パラパッパ
Chur-chur-chur, para-pappa,
ドン スタッ！ドン スタッダッ ミュージック！
Don sta! Don staddah music!
お祭り騒ぎは お嫌い？
Do you dislike festival commotion?
ドン スタッ！ドン スタッダッ ミュージック！
Don sta! Don staddah music!
さあ始めよう 調子合わせて 一せいのワオ！
Come on, let's start, get in the mood, altogether now, wow!
チュッチュッロリラ
Chu-chu-churorira,
同じ夜ほら
on the same night, look!
チュッチュッロリラ
Chu-chu-churorira,
青空のすぐ
right beneath the blue sky.
ドラマの退屈は 止んない！
The drama's boredom won't stop!
ドン スタッ！ドン スタッダッ ミュージック！ 飛んでくたばりましょう
Don sta! Don staddah music! Let's fly away and drop dead!
私は シンデレラ あなたは 王子様
I am Cinderella, you are the prince.
順繰り 近づいて 運命の番は ぐるぐる回る
Stepping closer one by one, fate's turn spins round and round.
そして 出番よ ほら モラトリアムに酔いしれて
And then it's our turn—look, get intoxicated by the moratorium!
憂き世を そっと抜け出して
Quietly slipping away from this floating world,
月が泣けば 二人のダンスフロア
when the moon weeps, it's our dance floor!
踊れ踊れや 境界線 恋と友情の真ん中で
Dance upon the boundary line, right between love and friendship.
指を結んで 心開いて もうちょっと夢を見ていたいのワオ！
Interlace your fingers, open your heart, I want to dream a little longer, wow!
チュッチュッロリラ
Chu-chu-churorira,
同じ夜ほら
on the same night, look!
チュッチュッロリラ
Chu-chu-churorira,
青空のすぐ
right beneath the blue sky.
鳴く鳴く鳴く こんな日々よ とにかく覚悟は止まらん！
Crying, weeping through days like this—anyway, my resolve won't stop!
ドン スタッ！ドン スタッダッ ミュージック！
Don stat! Don stat-dat music!
切ない愛に乗って
Riding on fleeting love,
自分探しだとか
searching for oneself,
生きてく意味だとか
or the meaning of life,
案外簡単ね 目前のあなたを独り占めしたい
surprisingly simple: I want to keep you all to myself right before my eyes.
ホントそれだけ
Truly, just that.
ねえ だから現実を投げ出して
Hey, so throw away reality,
浮世離れとかかこつけて
under the guise of detachment from the world.
闇夜の先に回るはミラーボール
Beyond the dark night, the mirror ball spins.
詠呼 所詮は絵空事だと
Ah, saying it's all just a pipe dream,
おとなこどもの真ん中で
right in the middle of adults and children,
妙に斜に構えてなんかないで
don't act all cynical and aloof,
ありのまんまさらして頂戴ワオ！
just bare your true self, wao!
特別な魔法が解けたら
When the special magic wears off,
また元通り戻ってゆくから
we'll return to the way we were, so
ほら モラトリアムに酔いしれて
Hey, getting intoxicated by the moratorium,
憂き世をそっと抜け出して
quietly slipping away from this fleeting world.
月が泣けば二人のダンスフロア
If the moon cries, it's our dance floor.
もっと踊って ここで踊って
Dance more, dance right here,
ほら モラトリアムに酔いしれて
Hey, getting intoxicated by the moratorium,
憂き世をそっと抜け出して
quietly slipping away from this fleeting world.
月が泣けば二人のダンスフロア
If the moon cries, it's our dance floor.
詠呼 踊り踊れや境界線
Ah, dance and dance across the boundary line,
恋と友情の真ん中で
right in the middle of love and friendship,
指を結んで心開いて
interlocking fingers and opening our hearts.
もうちょっと夢を見てたいのワオ！
I want to dream just a little longer, wao!
ドン スタッ！ドン スタッダッ ミュージック！
Don stat! Don stat-dat music!
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, I'm your doppelganger."
何の冗談か目をこすってみる
Rubbing my eyes, wondering what kind of joke this is.
影が二つ伸びて そしてまた幕は上がる
Two shadows stretch out, and once again the curtain rises.
「もう一人自分が居たらとあなたは言いました」
"You said, 'If only there were another me,'"
「そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼んだのさ」
"And that earnest wish is what summoned me."
そりゃ願ったとも 艱難辛苦すべての代理者エージェント
Of course I wished for it, agent representing all trials and tribulations.
過程はいいから結果を下さい
Forget the process, just give me the results.
無意味で無残な代償 ねえ こんなことより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろ？
Meaningless and gruesome compensation—hey, there are more important things than this, right?
「「ええ やります やります 何でもやります 僕は君の分身です」」
"Yeah, I'll do it, I'll do anything, I'm your doppelganger."
含み笑いで救世主メサイアは謳う
Smiling slyly, the savior messiah sings.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear doppelganger, who, who are you?
呻吟 混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Intersecting with groans and turbidity, who am I?
ねえ 有りもしない #0 と #1
Hey, non-existent #0 and #1,
証明の根拠なんて何処にも
there's no basis for proof anywhere.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear doppelganger, who, who are you?
芽生えた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice the budding existence.
鳴り止まない 醒めない
Never stopping, never waking up,
奇跡の輪廻が
the cycle of miracles
狂った正解を染め上げて
dyes the warped correct answer—
ルンパッパ
runpappa!
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
A strangely off Monday,
一つ二つと崩れてゆく辻褄が
inconsistencies collapsing one by one,
僕を中傷する
slandering me.
「お前は一体誰だ」と ちょっと待って
"Just who the hell are you?" Wait a minute,
知らない昨日 知りもしない言葉
yesterday I don't know, words I don't even recognize—
そうやっていつの間にやら
just like that, before I knew it,
影は溶けてゆく
the shadow melts away.
僕は何なんだろう
What on earth am I?
ねえ どうか存在を返して
Hey, please give my existence back.
「生憎様だが こっち側はこっち側で気分が良くて」
"Too bad for you, but it feels great on this side,"
「もうあなたの居場所は此処にはないこと分かってるんでしょ？」
"You know there's no place for you here anymore, right?"
「ねえ 奪われたんなら奪えばいいんだよ」
"Hey, if it was stolen from you, just steal it back,"
「今度は お前の番だから」
"Because this time it's your turn."
含み笑いで侵略者インベーダーは謳う
Smiling slyly, the invader sings.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear doppelganger, who, who are you?
呻吟 混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Intersecting with groans and turbidity, who am I?
まあ そりゃそうかそうだよな
Well, I suppose that's how it is.
命の椅子は一つだけ
There is only one chair of life.
「どうも こんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, nice to meet you, I'm your doppelganger."
何の 間違いか目を擦ってみる
Rubbing my eyes at the mistake,
影が二つ伸びて、そしてまた幕は上がる
Two shadows stretch out, and the curtain rises once more.
「もう一人自分がいらないとあなたは言いました」
"You said we didn't need another me,"
「そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼ぶのさ」
"That such earnest wishes called out to me."
そりゃ願ったとて
As if I'd wished for that!
艱難辛苦 全ての代行者エージェント
Hardship and toil, the stand-in agent for it all.
過程はいいから結果を下さい
Give me the result, never mind the process!
無意味で無意味な代償
Meaningless and senseless compensation.
ねえこんな事より大事なことがあるんだよ
Hey, isn't there something more important than this?
いいだろう
Fair enough!
「おやおやりますやります何でもやります 僕はあなたの分身です」
"Sure, I'll do it, I'll do anything, I'm your doppelganger."
含み笑いで救済者メサイアは謡う
Smirking, the savior Messiah mocks.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Greetings, Doppelganger, who are you?
嘶声 混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Cries and wails intertwining, who am I?
ねえ有りもしない#0と#1
Hey, there's not even a #0 or #1,
証明の根拠なんて何処にもない
And proof of existence is nowhere to be found.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？
Greetings, Doppelganger, who is who?
掠められた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world hasn't noticed this usurped existence.
鳴り止まない 目覚め止まない 奇跡の輪廻が
An endless ringing, an endless awakening, the miracle's reincarnation,
狂った正解を塗り上げて ルンパッパ
Coating a warped correct answer, run-pappa!
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Things feel a bit off this Monday,
一つ二つと崩れていく戒律が
The maxims are crumbling away one by one.
僕を猜疑する 「お前は一体誰だ」と
Doubtlessly targeting me, "Just who are you?"
ちょっと待って 知らない昨日 知りもしない言葉
Hold on a second, yesterday's unknown words,
そうやっていつの間にかやらは 影は溶けていく
Before I knew it, the shadow just melts away.
僕はなんだろうねえどうとか存在を返して
What on earth am I? Hey, give me back my existence!
「生憎だがこっちはこっちは随分心地よさ愛して」
"I hate you, but things are way more comfortable on this side."
「もうあなたの居場所は此処にはない事分かってるんでしょ」
"Your place isn't around here anymore, you know."
「ねえ奪われたなら奪えばいいだろう今度はあなたの番だから」
"Hey, if something was taken, just take it back, it's your turn now."
含み笑いで侵略者インベーダーは謡う
Smirking, the invader trespasser mocks.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Greetings, Doppelganger, who are you?
嘶声 混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Cries and wails intertwining, who am I?
まあそうりゃそうかそうだろうな 命の椅子は一つだけ
Well, I suppose that's how it is, there's only one chair of life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？
Greetings, Doppelganger, who is who?
零れ落ちた一粒 乾き果てる前に
Before that single spilled drop dries up,
誰でもいい何でもいい 器を下さい
Give me a vessel, I don't care who or what it is!
狂った正解を塗り上げて ルンパッパ
Coating a warped correct answer, run-pappa!
pray それはおぞうっと続く ヒトの業の連鎖
Pray, it just keeps going on endlessly, the chain of human sins.
pain 委ねあって許しあって 満たされ往く
Pain, entrusting and forgiving, fulfilling as we go.
背後にはシャッターの壁
There's a wall of shutters behind me,
指先は鉄の匂い
My fingertips smell like steel.
進め 弾け どのち混るでしょ
Move ahead, strum those strings, it's crowded at any rate!
find a way ここから
Find a way from here,
found out 見つける
Found out, find it,
rockを奏でろ
Play some rock,
遠くを見据えろ
Gaze into the distance.
最後には辿った あの壁
Finally, I reached that wall!
指先は鉄の匂い
My fingertips smell like iron.
進め 弾け
Push ahead, bounce along,
どの道ごむでしょう
which path will I be crossing?
find a way ここから
Find a way from here,
song for 歌うよ
Song for, I'll sing it out,
rockを響かせ
Rock, let it echo,
crowと歌うよ
Crow, I'll sing along!
いつまでもこんなところに居る?
How long will I exist in this place?
漆黒の羽にさらされて消えてくれ
Let the jet black wings carry you away and just disappear.
息継ぎさえできない街の中
I can't even keep going on this street where you can't catch your breath,
星空が最高の舞台
The starry sky is the best stage of all.
カラスたちがカーカーと鳴くよ
The crows cry out, "Caw, caw!"
いつも思うよ いつ寝てるんだろう
Always thinking of them, I wonder when they go to sleep.
find a way あたしも
Find a way - I'll find it too,
song for 歌うよ
Song for - I'll sing out,
rockを響かせ
Rock - making it echo,
crowと歌うよ
Crow - singing along!
いつまでこんな心にいる そういうやつもいつできがする
How long must I remain in such a dark place?
うるさいことだけで言うなら
If you can only say annoying things,
漆黒の羽にさらされて 消えてくれ
Let the jet black wings carry you away and just disappear!
全力でも倒れそうだ
I'm about to collapse from pure exhaustion,
指も擦り切れて痛い
My fingertips are worn out and aching,
でもね 演るよ今夜もビッグなストーリー
But I'll still perform tonight in this big story!
find a way ここから
Find a way from here,
found out 見つける
Found out, I'll find it,
rockを奏でろ
Play some rock,
遠くを見据えろ
Gaze into the distance!
背後にはシャッターの壁
Behind the shutter wall
指先は鉄の匂い
Fingertips smell of iron
進め弾けどの道混むでしょ find a way ここから
Find a way from here
found out 見つける rockを奏でろ
Find it, play rock
遠くを見据えろ
Look far away
息継ぎさえできない街の中で
In a city where you can't even breathe
星空が最高の舞台で
The starry sky is the best stage
カラスたちカーカーと鳴くよ
The crows caw loudly
いつも思ういつ寝てるんだろ
I always wonder when you'll sleep
find a way あたしも song for 歌うよ rockを響かせ crowと歌うよ
Find a way, sing for us, sound rock, sing with crows
いつまでこんなところに居る?
How long will you stay in a place like this?
そう言う奴もいた気がする
I feel like someone said that
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
If you only have complaints to make
漆黒の羽にさらされて消えてくれ
Be swept away by jet-black wings and vanish
重ねた手のひら 風の色はもう見えなくなっていく
Overlapping palms, the color of the wind fades away
怯えて震える 身体を焼き尽くしていく
Trembling with fear, burning up my body
もう何もかも信じたくは無い i don't believe it anymore cause i feel sad
I don't want to believe in anything anymore...
記憶を辿ったって何も変わらないよ
Tracing memories changes nothing at all
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
おいでおいで ブタさん ウサギさん キツネさん に ぞうさん
Come on, pig, rabbit, fox, and elephant!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
チーター さん は かけっこ じゃまけないぞ
Cheetah won't lose in a race!
過去を消し去るように 疾走れ don't give a fxxk with me
Run to erase the past, don't give a fxxk with me!
狂いきったイメージと 絶望の隙間に消え落ちていく
Fading into the gap between a manic image and despair
零れ落ちた闇雲のアンサー まだ見つからないまま
The spilled answer of dark clouds, still not found yet
風の色はもう見えないけど 前までは見えてた 怖っ (^)!'%&#
The wind's color is gone, but I could see it before... how scary!
何て?
What?
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
おいでおいで ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Come on, let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Let Wani-san join the group too!
分かり合えない 生き物としての カテゴライズの壁
The wall of categorization as creatures who cannot understand each other
乾いた果実も 一度乾くと もう戻れない
Dried fruit once dried can never go back
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
そろそろ ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
It's about time you let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
さすがに 気の毒になってくる
It's getting genuinely pitiful
思いやりという名の 道徳的価値の再認識
Re-recognizing moral values called consideration
ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Let Wani-san join the group too!
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
おいでおいで ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Come on, let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Let Wani-san join the group too!
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
おいでおいで ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Come on, let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Let Wani-san join the group too!
分かり合えない 生き物としての カテゴライズの壁
Even if we can't truly understand one another as living beings
乾いた果実も 一度乾くと もう戻れない
Dried fruit once dried can never go back to how it was
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
そろそろ ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
It's about time you let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
おなか ぽんぽんぽん の やっ ほー
Tummy pon-pon-pon, yaho!
さすがに気後ずくんだって来る 思いやりという名の
Surely, we must be longing for it deep down
ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
Let Wani-san join the group too!
どうぶつさんたち 大集合だ わいわい
Animal friends, big gathering, yay yay!
そろそろ ワニさん も なかまに いれて あげて
It's about time you let Wani-san join the group too!
みんなで楽しく うん パッパ の ぶんぶん
Everyone having fun, un-pappa bun-bun!
baby baby baby baby
君の胸にキスをしたら
If I kissed you on your chest,
君はどんな声だすだろう
I wonder what kind of voice you'd make.
白い塩素ナトリウム
White chlorine and sodium,
水色の水着を溶かすなよ
Don't melt your light-blue swimsuit.
君を乗せた宇宙船が
The spaceship carrying you
夕暮れの彼方へ消えて
fades away into the sunset's horizon.
光るプラネタリウム
A glowing planetarium.
いっそこのこと僕を吸い込んでよ
You might as well just swallow me up.
君に彼氏がいたら悲しい だけど
If you had a boyfriend, I'd be sad, but...
「君が好き」だと言う
Just saying "I like you"
それだけで僕は嬉しいのさ
is enough to make me happy.
まぼろしみたいなメリーゴーランド
A merry-go-round like an illusion,
一瞬が永遠に感じて
making a fleeting moment feel eternal.
僕の汗のにおいが
I felt like the scent of my sweat
君にばれたような気がした
was managed and given away to you.
君に彼氏がいたら悲しい だけど
If you had a boyfriend, I'd be sad, but...
いたら悲しいけど
If you had one, I'd be sad, but...
「君が好き」だと言う
Just saying "I like you"
それだけで僕は嬉しいのさ
is enough to make me happy.
夢で逢えたら いいな
If I could meet you in a dream, that'd be nice.
君の笑顔にときめいて
My heart flutters at your smile.
夢で逢えたら いいな
If I could meet you in a dream, that'd be nice,
夜の波をこえてゆくよ
I'll cross over the waves of the night.
君に好きな人がいたら悲しい だけど
If you had someone you loved, I'd be sad, but...
君を想うことが
Just thinking about you,
それだけが僕のすべてなのさ
that alone is my everything.
That alone is my everything.
夏の終わりが君をさらっていく
The end of summer carries you away,
君の香りだけを残して
leaving behind only your scent.
夏の終わりが君をさらっていく
The end of summer carries you away,
夜の波をこえてゆくよ
I'll cross over the waves of the night.
夢で逢えたら いいな
If I could meet you in a dream, that'd be nice.
君の笑顔にときめいて
My heart flutters at your smile.
夢で逢えたら いいな
If I could meet you in a dream, that'd be nice,
夜の波をこえてゆくよ
I'll cross over the waves of the night.
baby
ここまで本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming this far.
自分伝えられたと思うけど
I feel like I was able to convey it, but
でもまだ伝えきれてません。
I still haven't conveyed it all yet.
世界はそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ。
That's why the world calls that love.
涙の中にかすかな灯りがともったら
When a faint light is lit amid my tears,
君の目の前で温めてたこと話すのさ
I'll talk about what I kept warm right before your eyes.
それでも僕らの声が乾いていくだけなら
Still, if our voices are just going to dry up,
朝が来るまでせめて誰かと歌いたいんだ
I want to sing with someone at least until morning comes.
昨日のあなたが嘘だと言うなら
If you say yesterday's you was a lie,
昨日の景色を捨てちまうだけだ
I'll just throw away yesterday's scenery.
新しい日々を変えるのは
What changes each new day
僕らが確かめ合う
is us confirming it together.
世界じゃそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ
In this world, that's called love.
心の声をつなぐのがこれ程怖いモノだとは
Connecting the voices of our hearts is so frightening,
今までの過去なんてなかったかのように歌い出すんだ
but we'll sing out as if our past never existed.
僕らはいつれ誰かを疑いちまうから
Since we'll end up doubting someone eventually,
せめて今だけ美しい歌を歌うのさ
let's at least sing a beautiful song right now.
悲しい言葉では
With sad words,
何も変わらないんだぜ
nothing will ever change.
奴らが何をしていたっていうんだ
What is it they're even trying to do?
昨日のあなたが裏切り者なら
If yesterday's you was a betrayer,
昨日の景色を忘れちまうだけだ
I'll just forget yesterday's scenery.
新しい日々を変えるのは愛らしほとの愛なのさ
What changes each new day is a love so endearing.
僕らそれを確かめ合う世界じゃそれも愛と呼ぶんだぜ
We confirm it together; in this world, that too is called love.
僕らが新しい日々を思うときに、僕らはどうしても愛という言葉を使ってしまうわけですよ。
When we think of new days, we somehow end up using the word "love."
心の声と、あなたの憎しみと、うたぎりを、愛と言いたいわけですよ。
We want to call the voice of our hearts, your hatred, and our suspicions "love."
愛と平和！
Love and peace!
悲しみで花が咲くものか！
As if flowers could bloom from sadness!
新しい日々の僕たちは確かな予感がしてるのさ
We have a certain premonition about our new days.
涙の中に かすかな灯りが とまったら
When a faint light is lit amid my tears,
君の目の前で あたためてた 話すのさ
I talk, before your eyes, about how it warmed me.
それでも 僕等の 声が 乾いていく だけなら
If our voices are just going to dry up anyway,
朝が来るまで せめて 誰かと 歌いたいんだ
I want to at least sing with someone until the morning comes.
昨日の あなたが 嘘だと 言う ならば
If you were fake yesterday,
昨日の 景色を 捨ててしまう だけだ
then I'm just going to throw the scenery of yesterday away.
新しい 日々を つなぐ のは
What connects each new day
新しい 君と僕 なのさ
is the new you and me.
僕等 なぜか 確かめ合う
For some reason we make sense of each other;
世界 じゃ それを 愛 と 呼ぶ ん だ ぜ
in this world, that's called love.
心の 声を つなぐ のが
What connects the voices of our hearts
これ程 怖い モノ だ と は
is the things we fear so much.
君と僕 が 声を 合わせる
You and I raise our voices together,
今までの 過去なんて なかったかのように 歌い出すんだ
singing out as if our past never existed.
ラブ＆ピース！ラブ＆ピース！ラブ＆ピース！
Love & peace! Love & peace! Love & peace!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ラバーバンドビーズ！ラバーバンドビーズ！
Rubber band beads! Rubber band beads!
というわけで、改めてまして尾丸ポルカです！ここ駆け出し…ありがとうございました！
So, once again, I'm Omaru Polka! Thank you for running all the way here with me!
というわけで、こちらからは…、えっと、これからはですね、あ、これからは！
And so, from here on... um, from now on, oh, from now on!
えー、お決まり！誕生日記念グッズ出ますのグッズ紹介だ！
Uh, as usual, it's time for the birthday commemorative goods introduction!
どうぞ！いけ、ラバーバンドビーズ！
Here we go! Go, rubber band beads!
ラバーバンドビーズ出たー！誕生日記念2024、こちら、ドドドッと情報量が多すぎるさ！
Rubber band beads are out! Birthday Commemoration 2024, there's so much info here!
いっこいっこ整理していこうか。
Let's go through it one by one.
まずはですね、こちらになっております。はい！大迫力のポルカをお楽しみください！
First is this one. Yes! Enjoy a powerful Polka!
フルグラフィックTシャツでございます。
It's the full-graphic T-shirt.
南野あき先生描き下ろしとなっております。こちらハッピーのね、生地も良くてね、また新しい服が増えてポルカ、あの、クローゼットにしまっておけば、
Illustrated by Akisensei Minamino. The fabric is nice, and with new clothes added, Polka can keep them in her closet—
いつでも頼れるって感じでいいんじゃないでしょうか！
so you can always count on them, how's that!
そして次、こちら！はい、愛らしくてスリムなかたちのクリアボトル！
And next, this one! Yes, a cute, slim clear bottle!
可愛い！これね、あの、いつものとはちょっと違う形の、なんだろうね、スリムな、クリアな、あの四角っぽい感じの素材になっております。こちらもぜひ、よろしくお願いいたします！
Cute! This has a slightly different shape than usual, kind of a slim, clear, square-like material. Please check this out too!
今日のロゴだね。続いて、こちら！ででーん！
Today's logo. Next, this one! Ta-da!
これも今日のロゴじゃい！ちょっとそこまで、あ、ちょっとそこまでのほうじゃなかった！おしゃれすぎるポルカのラバーバンド！
This is today's logo too! A little out there... oh, not quite that far! Polka's ultra-stylish rubber band!
バッグにね、ギュッとつけるもよし、腕にギュッとつけて現地に行くもよし！うん、ボタンで止められます。完璧！
You can attach it tightly to your bag, or put it on your arm and head to the venue! Yep, it fastens with buttons. Perfect!
はい、そしてこちら！これだね、ちょっとそこまでポルカのミニサコッシュ！あ、いいね！
Yes, and this one! This is it, Polka's "a little trip" mini sacoche! Ah, nice!
もうスマホと、なんかちょっとお金入ればいいよねって人は、これを、どうぞ！はい、お土産にって感じのコーナーでした。
If you just need your phone and a little cash, here you go! Yes, this was the "souvenir" corner.
まだまだ続きます。そしてさらに、こちら！
It still continues. And furthermore, this one!
はい、シチュエーションボイスは「本番前の作戦会議！！」を僕らしましたよね、そういえば、ね。したよね、覚えてるかな？覚えてるね、うん、それを勝手にロゴのさしっていただきました、っていうのは嘘って言って手で、はい、って言う、
Yes, the situation voice is "Strategy Meeting Before the Show!!" We did that together, come to think of it. Right? Remember? You remember, yeah, I secretly used that for the logo—that's a lie, wait, using my hands, yeah, saying...
っていうてのシチュエーションボイスになっておりまーす！
...is what kind of situation voice it is!
はい、それでは最後にフルセット購入特典、こちら！直筆サイン＆箔押しメッセージ入りポストカード！そして特典、特典ボイスはまだだったな、うん、今度せいにしてしまったな、どうしようかな。
Yes, and finally, the full set purchase bonus, this one! Postcard with handwritten signature and foil-stamped message! And the bonus... bonus voice wasn't ready yet, oh, I messed that up, what should I do.
これはね、特典ボイスもあるんだよ、実は。みてくれ、きみたち。え、直筆サインも合えば、特典ボイスもある！
There's actually a bonus voice too, you know. Look at this, you guys. If you get the handwritten signature, there's also a bonus voice!
お疲れ様を伝えたくて、で、わ！ね！ま、いまはね、ちょっと、まあ、そういうこともあるんだけど、まあ、ね、そういえばこともあるんだけど、あの、あるんですよ、実 ボイスっていうものがね！はい、ね、あってさ、そう、素晴らしい！いや、ありがとう！うん、みんな！
I wanted to say "good work," and, well! Right? Well, right now, there are things like that, but, well, yeah, there are things like that, but there actually is a voice thing, you know! Yes, right, there is, so, wonderful! Yeah, thanks! Yeah, everyone!
じゃあ、これをね、ぜひこのあと販売するようなので、よろしくお願いします！
So, since this will be on sale after this, please look forward to it!
はい！すべての、えー、品が揃ったということで、えー、最後の最後に最後の最後に、もう一曲だけ歌わせてくだサーイ！魂の響き！みんな、まだいけるか！
Yes! With all the items ready, uh, for the very, very, very last part, please let me sing just one more song! Echo of the soul! Everyone, can you still go?!
盛り上がれっか！聞こえてんぞー！よろしくお願いします！
Can you get hyped?! I can hear you! Thank you very much!
はい！ふっ！
Yes! Ha!
何回でも言えます！みんな今日は、本当にありがとう！
I can say it a million times! Thank you all so much today!
届いてますかー！
Is it reaching you?!
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Accustomed to this cataclysmic madness,
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
I mistake this daily life for peace.
ランブリングコースター揺さぶられながら
As this rambling coaster jolts me back and forth,
見失えないものはなんだ？
What is it that I mustn't lose sight of?
平等原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Drunk on the concept of fundamental equalism,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my soul feels like it's et cetera.
大嫌い大好きちゃんと喋らなきゃ
Love it or hate it, you gotta say it clearly,
人形とさして変わらないし
Or you're no different from a doll.
宵街を往く人かかりは
Crowds of people walking the streets at night,
嬉しそうだったり寂しそうだったり
Some seem happy, while others seem lonely.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
The contrast jumps around the musical staff,
歌とリズムになる
Turning into song and rhythm.
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビーターステップ
Marmalade and sugar song, peanuts and bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
So sweet and acrid it makes my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
To make it a night that will astonish the world.
i feel 上々
I feel fantastic,
連鎖になってリフレクト
Reflecting in a chain.
蓋然性合理主義の正論に揉まれて
Tossed about by the sound reasoning of rationalism,
僕らの音楽は道具に成り下がる？
Has our music been reduced to mere tools?
こっちを向いてよ、背を向けないでよ
Come on, look this way, don't turn your back on me,
それは正論にならないけど
Though that may not be a sound argument.
祭囃子のその其処で
Right there amidst the festival music,
昂ったままの人
The people still hyped up,
泣き出してしてしまう人
And the people bursting into tears,
多分同じだろう
Are probably all the same.
でも言葉にしようものなら
But the moment I try to put it into words,
拙さが極まり
The clumsiness is extreme.
最高だってシュガーソング
It's fabulous, this sugar song,
幸せってビーターステップ
It's happiness, this bitter step.
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason why we can't die right there,
惜しかったって等速で
At a constant speed despite the regrets,
明日は来ちまうけど
Tomorrow will come anyway.
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
If the forecast in our minds has finished updating,
someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday when the mania quiets down,
someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday when valid arguments lose meaning,
feeling song ＆ step
The feeling song and step
鳴らし続けることだけが
Just continuing to ring out
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる、Q.E.D.!
Will be the proof that makes us who we are, Q.E.D.!
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビーターステップ
Marmalade and sugar song, peanuts and bitter step,
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason for living right there,
北北東は後方へ、その距離が誇らしい
Leaving the north-northeast behind, proud of that distance.
世界中を、驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep astonishing the whole world!
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビーターステップ
Marmalade and sugar song, peanuts and bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
So sweet and acrid it makes my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
To make it a night that will astonish the world.
i feel 上々
I feel fantastic,
連鎖になってリフレクト
Reflecting in a chain.
交差点で息絶えた今日の
Today's sunset at the intersection,
散々だった散々な夕暮れがハッピーエンド
That miserable, wretched twilight becomes a happy ending.
響くよメロディ
The melody echoes on.